but what about the reliability and the
MTTF
of red one same as before we will assume
that some F is the failure rate for a
single disk in failures per disk per
second and for a single disk remember
that the MTTF is simply 1 over F where F
is that failure rate and then the mean
time to data loss which is the MTTF
really of the whole disk array in this
case just one disk would be simply the
MTTF of that one disk well let's say now
that we have two disks in raid 1 and
remember that the failure rate when we
have more than one disk is n times the
failure rate of one disk as long as all
of the disks are working so what we have
really is that both of our disks in raid
1 are ok until the time MTTF of one disk
over 2 this is the expected time when
one of the disks will fail now unlike
raid 0 where this is the point where it
would lose data now we have mirroring so
both of the disks need to fail in order
for the whole thing to lose data one
failure is not data loss yet so we don't
have the failure of the array yet but at
this time we are down to one disk that
one disk is a working disk and has this
failure rate so that one remaining this
will live on for another MTTF of a
single disk this is very important to
understand if we have a working disk at
some point in time the MTTF for that
disk is going to be the overall MTTF for
one disk this MTTF is not affected by
the fact that this disk has already been
working for all this time why well
because the failure rate is constant
it's not affected by time so if we have
a working disk its failure rate is
always the same the only thing that
changes the failure rate is if the disk
fails so if we had two disks and both
work this is the expected time of them
surviving and then if we're down to one
this that works at the time when we have
a single working disk this is the MTTF
that we can expect so overall the mean
time to data loss for raid one with two
disks is going to be the MTTF of a
single disk over two plus the MTTF of a
single disk and now we bought two disks
and use them in an array that has the
capacity of only a single disk so
basically paid for the extra disk just
to get reliability and what we get is
just one half more of the MTTF that we
would normally get with only a single
disk so what's the point the point is
that this calculation assumes that no
disk is replaced at the time when it
fails so we had a failure and we just
let that fail disk be there and we were
down to one disk and didn't fix it and
then we just were down to the MTTF of
one disk for a while but remember that
when we want reliability we definitely
will replace the failed disks so when we
have the first failure we will as soon
as possible replace that fail disk copy
the data from the working disk to it so
now we are back to raid 1 working
properly
so what's the MTTF for that